Dwight Anderson Williams II, PhD

Curriculum Vitæ Summary Extended Curriculum Vitæ

ORCID: 0000-0003-2611-2388 arXiv: arxiv.org/a/williams_d_5.html Website: www.mathdwight.com Email: Dwight.WilliamsII@morgan.edu Department of Mathematics Morgan State University 1700 E Cold Spring Lane, Baltimore, MD 21251

Professional Appointments

2023-curr	Assistant Professor, Morgan State University.
2022-2023	Visiting Assitant Professor, Pomona College.
2022-2022	Facilitator, Charles A. Dana Center (Math Leaders 4 Racial Justice).
2020-2021	Postdoc Research Associate, Iowa State University. Supervisor: Michael Young.
2021-2021	Postdoctoral Research Advisor , Mathematical Sciences Research Institute (MSRI-UP). Supervisors: Rebecca E. Garcia & Pamela E. Harris.
2016-2020	Graduate Teaching Assistant, The University of Texas at Arlington.

Education

- 2016–2020 **PhD in Mathematics**, The University of Texas at Arlington. Advisor: Dimitar Grantcharov.
- 2012-2014 MS in Pure Mathematics, The Florida State University.
- 2008–2012 **BS in Mathematics**, Florida A&M University.

Research Highlights

Co-author names: pre-baccalaureate/pre-doctoral by date of submission

In Mathematics

2023 Interval and \(\ell \)-interval Rational Parking Functions (Manuscript).

arXiv: 2311.14055.

Aguilar-Fraga, T; Elder, J; Garcia, RE; Hadaway, KP; Harris, PE; Harry, KJ; Hogan, IB; Johnson, J; Kretschmann, J; Lawson-Chavanu, K; Martínez Mori, JC; Monroe, CD; Quiñonez, D; Tolson III, D

2023 On parking functions and the Tower of Hanoi.

American Mathematical Monthly. DOI: 10.1080/00029890.2023.2206311.

Aguillon, Y; Alvarenga, D; Harris, PE; Kotapati, S; Martínez Mori, JC; Monroe, CD; Saylor, Z; Tieu, C; Williams II, DA.

2023 Ghost center and representations of the diagonal reduction algebra of $\mathfrak{osp}(1|2)$.

Journal of Geometry and Physics. DOI: 10.1016/j.geomphys.2023.104788.

Hartwig, JT; Williams II, DA.

2022 Diagonal reduction algebra for $\mathfrak{osp}(1|2)$.

Theoretical and Mathematical Physics. DOI: 10.1134/S0040577922020015 (English) DOI: 10.4213/tmf10138 (Russian) Hartwig, JT; Williams II, DA.

In Education

- Informing Change: Stories of Graduate Students from Underrepresented Groups in Mathematics Doctoral Programs.

 Association for the Study of Higher Education 46th General Conference. Program book

 Westine, C; Sword, S; Young, M; Bartel, M; Williams II, DA; Harris, PE.
- 2021 Studying Successful Doctoral Students in Mathematics from Underrepresented Groups.

Accelerating Systemic Change Network (ASCN) & Network of STEM Education Centers (NSEC) Transforming Institutions Conference 2021. Poster webpage

Sword, S; Young, M; Westine, C; Winger, A; Bartel, M; Williams II, DA; McRoberts, C; Sisneros-Thiry, S; Gates, M; Harris, PE.

Exposition

2022 People Over Math: A Co-created Principle for Successful Research Communities.

MAA FOCUS. Digital edition

Garcia, RE; Harris, PE; Williams II, DA; Martínez Mori, JC; Monroe, CD; Aguilar-Fraga, T; Aguillon, Y; Alofamoni Quiñonez, D; Alvarenga, D; Celestine, A; Gill, P; Hogan, IB; Johnson, J; Lawson-Chavanu, K; Liu, L; Ortiz, A; Quesada, L; Rivera Sánchez, CM; Soto, C; Tieu, C; Tolson III, D; van der Leeuw, J; Vargas, P.

Instructor of Record

Morgan State University

Graduate: MATH 505 Abstract Algebra I, MATH 506 Abstract Algebra II.

Undergraduate: MATH 413 Algebraic Structures, MATH 431 Mathematical Theory of Statistics, MATH 432 Mathematical Theory of Statistics II.

Pomona College

Undergraduate: MATH PO 032 Calculs III, MATH 101 PO Introduction to Analysis, MATH 171 PO Abstract Algebra I: Groups & Rings

The University of Texas at Arlington

Undergraduate: MATH 1302 College Algebra, MATH 1316 Mathematics for Economics and Business Analysis, MATH 1421 Preparation for Calculus, MATH 2326 Calculus III, MATH 3330 Introduction to Matrics & Linear Algebra

Advising

Undergrad

- 2024-curr. Twymun Safford, Morgan State University. MANIM.
- 2024-curr. Angeluis Sayavongsa-Vaughn, Morgan State University. MANIM.
- 2023-2023 Irmak Bukey, Pomona College. MANIM (reduction algebras).
- 2023-2023 Gisele Umutoni, Pomona College. MANIM (trees and proofs).
- 2022-2023 Irmak Bukey, Pomona College. Senior Thesis: Reduction Algebras: Verifying Solutions to Laplace's Equation.
- 2022-2023 Andrew Shannon, Pomona College. Senior Theis: The Diffie-Hellman Problem in Lie Algebras Revisited.
- 2021-2021 Aaron Ortiz, Mathematical Sciences Research Institute (MSRI-UP). Research Report: The defective parking space.
- 2021-2021 Lauren J. Quesada, Mathematical Sciences Research Institute (MSRI-UP). Research Report: The defective parking space.
- 2021–2021 Cynthia Marie Rivera Sánchez, Mathematical Sciences Research Institute (MSRI-UP). Research Report: The defective parking space.
- 2021-2021 Tomás Aguilar-Fraga, Mathematical Sciences Research Institute (MSRI-UP). Research Report: ℓ-Interval parking functions.
- 2021-2021 Kobe Lawson-Chavanu, Mathematical Sciences Research Institute (MSRI-UP). Research Report: ℓ-Interval parking functions.
- 2021-2021 Dirk Tolson III, Mathematical Sciences Research Institute (MSRI-UP). Research Report: ℓ-Interval parking functions.

Organizing Currently

- 2024 Fresh Researchers in Algebra, Combinatorics, and Topology Active Learning Seminar.
- 2024 AMS Spring Eastern Sectional (Howard University) Special Session